Remember when I introduced you guys to
this radio frequency machine a few years
ago? The one that pretty much started it
all for me on this channel? Well, it's
back. Yep. I've taken it out of its box.
I've dusted off the probes. And I'm
ready to show all of you newbies to my
channel why this was my OG skin
tightening device and why it's still one
of the most powerful, if not slightly
evil, skin tightening machines that I
have ever owned. Today, we're going to
take a dive into the tech that's
contained within this device and why
it's my not so secret favorite skin
tightening treatment for achieving a
firmer, more youthful appearance. And
yes, I'm the voice of experience when it
comes to this machine. It's literally
been in my life for almost 4 years,
which really, when you think about how
affordable this one is, it's probably
one of the best investments I ever made
into my skincare. Now, if this is your
first time of seeing me and this device
right here, I'm TJ. I'm a total skincare
nerd, dedicated skincare device tester,
and trainy esthetician. I'm in my 40s,
so I understand the complexities that
come with the aging face and neck. And
if you wind things back right to the
start of my channel up till today,
you'll see that a lot of what I do
actually really has worked. So, if
you're ready, let's go.
So, it's a well-known fact that as we
age, collagen production in the body
slows down. Now, collagen is basically
the scaffolding of our skin that help
keep things elevated, firm, and plump.
But when those levels start to drop, so
does the skin. And wrinkles, laxity, and
sagging can all start to show up. Enter
radio frequency. Now, this technology
uses radio waves to gently heat the
deeper layers of the skin. And this
controlled thermal damage creates a
process called collagen remodeling.
Think of it like a bit of a wakeup call
for your skin cells, reminding them to
ramp up collagen production. So, I guess
the big question, does radio frequency
really work? I mean, the answer is a
resounding yes. Studies and my face have
shown just how effective radio frequency
can be when it comes to skin tightening
and collagen production. And it's
actually been shown to effectively help
to minimize the visible signs of aging,
including fine lines and wrinkles. And
it improves skin laxity, which basically
is going to give you a firmer and more
lifted appearance. But how much in the
way of results can you really expect to
get from home use radio frequency? Now,
obviously an incl clinic professional
device is going to give you way more
significant results in a faster amount
of time. But that's not to say that home
use radio frequency skin tightening
devices don't work because they do. And
just to kind of draw a little bit of
light on this, this is me at the start
of my channel. And the only tool that I
was really using at this point was radio
frequency. I was just getting started
with it. But if you look at my skin, it
is covered in lines. It's covered in
wrinkles. It's creping. It's sagging.
It's dropping. It's just looking really
loose. And if you're thinking, well,
he's probably had a load of surgery done
on his face. He's full of fillers. No.
The only thing that I've actually
changed on my face since I started my
channel are my two front teeth, which I
had crowns because I didn't like the way
they went backwards. But I've not had
any surgery whatsoever on my face. I
don't have any fillers in my face.
Occasionally, I do have a bit of Botox.
At the moment, I do have some Botox only
in my forehead. And this is for a little
bit of an experiment that I'm running
about whether radio frequency actually
causes Botox to break down and stop
working faster than if you don't have
radio frequency applied over the top of
it. So it's mainly for the science, but
also I don't hate the way it works in my
forehead. But other than the addition of
a little bit of Botox in my forehead
right now, absolutely everything on my
face and my neck has been transformed
with the use of home use devices. And
there's been a lot of consistency,
dedication, and education along the way,
which has given me a really deep
understanding of how the devices work,
what I can expect from them, and which
ones are going to work best for my own
unique situation. But when it comes to
skincare results, whilst with radio
frequency, you are going to see some
immediate results. Don't expect an
overnight miracle because the thing with
collagen denaturation and regeneration
is that it can take from 6 weeks up to 3
months to really reach its kind of peak
output. And that's when you're going to
notice the results kind of really
kicking in at their best.
Now, when looking at the studies for
radio frequency, most of the studies
actually recommend multiple treatments
to see the best results. And I can
confirm from my own personal experience
and from within my working environment
that this is true. Typically, you're
going to space out each of the
treatments between four and 6 weeks so
that the collagen has a chance to kind
of be depleted and then start
regenerating. With each consecutive
treatment, what happens then is that the
weaker collagen strands are kind of
broken down and removed by the body and
then replaced with fresh collagen. After
a couple of professional grade
treatments, then your skin should be
good to go for at least the next year.
But if you're like me and you kind of
want to see the best results, then
maintenance treatments are always
recommended. Now, I do use a lot of home
use radio frequency devices as well, and
these are designed to be used three to
four times a week. The heat generated by
these devices is at a much lower level
than with the professional grade devices
which makes them safer to use in the
long term. And basically what these home
use devices are doing are targeting the
more superficial layers within the
epidermis and the dermis giving you
those instant skin tightening and
plumping results that people are looking
for. And then over time they do help
with an increase in collagen and elastin
production which is going to give you a
visibly more youthful appearance.
So, a question I see quite often is, is
radio frequency skin tightening safe?
This is a treatment that's been around
for decades, has been closely studied,
it's been looked at in the long term,
and it's generally considered as a super
safe skin remodeling treatment. Now, it
can cause some temporary redness and
swelling, which is to be expected with
any kind of thermal damage, but when
it's used as directed, it's actually a
really safe and effective skin
treatment. And unless you're using a
clinical grade monopolar radio frequency
device that can actually reach into the
subcutaneous fat layer, your fat stores
are going to be pretty safe. So yeah,
it's not really something to be too
concerned about, especially when it
comes to using home use devices.
All right, let's talk about my generic
ride or die OG radio frequency skin
tightening device. This is the bipolar
device. It's a generic brand. It's
unbranded. Now, while it looks compact
and like that it's not going to deliver
much in the way of a radio frequency
treatment, it actually delivers a super
powerful heat output. And not only that,
it can also be a little bit spiteful at
times. Now, the radio frequency sparking
that this can create if you lose contact
with the skin. It's almost like being
zapped by electricity or pinged with a
red hot rubber band. It's more
surprising than painful, but when it
happens and you're using it on a high
heat output, yeah, not the most pleasant
experience, but I found that really
layering up on the conductive gel and
just making sure that you're keeping
really good contact with the skin kind
of avoids that issue. But yeah, this
device is an absolute powerhouse when it
comes to at home skin tightening. Now,
you have got interchangeable probes on
this device, so you can change it out
for the larger body probe or you can use
the smaller probe, which is designed for
use on the face. really good for
reaching up around the orbital rim area
and getting really deep along under the
jawline and that for that sculpting and
kind of lifting that you want in this
area. But whether you're looking to
tackle the fine lines and wrinkles
around your eyes or tighten up where
you've got a little bit of jowlling
coming on, this is by far one of the
best machines that I have for tackling
those regions and for hooded eyelids.
This literally deals with them in one
fell swoop. So, are you starting to see
why I love this so much? Now, obviously,
I could sit here and talk up about this
device and tell you how great it is for
lifting the skin, for dealing with the
hooded eyes, for kind of boosting all of
that collagen production, but as I like
to say in all of my videos, the proof is
in the pudding, which is why I'm going
to do a demo of this. Now, I haven't
done a demo with this radio frequency
skin tightening device on my channel for
the last couple of years because I've
really been focusing more on my premium
at home skincare devices, but I'm in one
of those moods where I kind of want to
go back in the past a little bit and
bring you guys back to some of the
technology that really kickstarted
everything for me. The technology that
actually made a real difference to my
skin at the beginning when it was at its
worst. Because while I am now coming on
to 4 years into my skincare journey, I
know that a lot of you guys are just
looking at taking your first steps and
while technology has definitely evolved
since I first started, there's still a
lot of benefits to be had from these
more original devices that are
definitely at a lower price point. So, I
guess I'm going to do a demo. Woohoo.
So, when it comes to radio frequency,
the first thing you're going to want to
do before you do a treatment is give
your skin a really good clean just to
make sure that nothing is going to be
preventing the frequency from entering
the skin. So, that means removing any
sunscreen, any makeup, any dirt or grime
on your face. The next thing that you're
going to want to do is apply a really
generous layer of conductive gel. Now,
the one that I use is from Medicube.
This is the HR booster gel. This is the
gel that I use with any of my energy
based frequencies, whether it is radio
frequency, whether it's EMS, whether
it's microcurrent. This basically
enables the frequency from the device to
penetrate through into the skin and work
its magic. Now, the areas that I really
want to focus on today with this device
are around my jawline.
So, a really nice thick layer I want to
do under the jawline, onto the chin. I
want to take care of my upper eyelid
area. By doing this, I'm lifting the
eyelid skin up onto the brow bone and
I'm able to tighten it. It's going to
really open my eyes. You guys are going
to see just how amazing this is for
that. And then I just want a little bit
of a volume boost in my cheeks just to
help soften and lift out my nose and
labial area.
So, I've got the probe here. To turn
this device on, first of all, you're
going to power it up at the back. So,
turn it on. The next thing you're going
to do is you're going to select your
intensity level. Now, as a general rule,
when I'm doing my jawline and my jowls,
I'm going to be using a level four or a
five. When I'm treating around the upper
eyelid area, I'm dropping down onto
about a three because the heat is really
intense in this area, and it generates
and builds really quickly with this
device. So, I'm going to do my gels and
jawline first. So, I'm just going to
bring this up to a four. Now, the device
at the moment is not active. The lights
here are static. They're not blinking.
To activate the frequency, all you do is
you push the onoff button. The lights
begin to blink. That means that the
frequency is now active. Now, I've
learned with this device, the worst
thing you can do is have the machine
active and then go and touch it with the
tip because the machine is going to bite
you. So, turn it off first,
place the probe to the skin, and then
on. And immediately, I can feel this
heat building. And it's really, really
quick and really intense.
Just focusing on my prejel area at the
moment. Just going to put this down now.
small circular motions
slowly gliding along backwards and
forwards. I want to build that heat in
the area as much as possible. For me,
the way that I work out when I've
reached the right temperature is that it
starts to just become slightly
unbearable. I don't want it to be
painful, but I also don't want it to be
no sensation at all because that means
that I've not generated the right level
of heat in there. Now, this device that
I have here is able to reach
temperatures of 60° C. Now, the 60° C is
absolutely optimal for collagen
remodeling, but it's also not necessary
for a home use device normally. And
you'll notice that I really focus my
attention here, and I give each area, I
want to kind of build that temperature
and hold it in each of the areas for a
good two to three minutes, just
backwards and forwards.
All
right,
slide it backwards and forwards now
along the jawbone.
Moving up slightly as I go.
[Music]
Now, like I said earlier, looking at the
studies and the information and from my
own personal experience, fat loss isn't
something you need to be worrying about
with home use devices. I've been using
radio frequency personally on my skin
over the last four years now and I've
not experienced a single bit of fat
loss. Yes, my face has changed shape
slightly. That a lot of that is down to
the increase in collagen that I have in
my skin now. Also, I did put a little
bit of weight on which, you know, is
always going to help, but I've never
personally lost any facial fat. Now,
obviously, I can't 100% guarantee that
it's not going to happen. And really,
the only person that you should be
talking to that about is your medical
practitioner because that's not me.
Okay, I feel like I kind of built enough
heat in the upper gel part. So, I'm just
going to go along the jawbone now. Just
keeping it moving backwards and
forwards.
And I'm going up on the gonial angle.
Sliding along the jawbone just for that
tightening of the skin there. Oh, I
forgot how quickly the heat builds in
this.
Okay, so let's do the other side.
Whoa. So, I don't know if you guys just
saw that, but the smoke was coming off
of this.
That is what I'm on about when it bites.
Okay,
there we go.
So, obviously you've seen me do the
other side, so I'm just going to kind of
fast forward through this bit just so
that you're not kind of sat here forever
waiting for me to get through with it.
[Music]
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going
to give myself a couple of minutes on
each of my upper eye areas. Now if you
take a look at the way that they're
looking right now, they're not in bad
condition, but I could do with them
being a little bit more open and lifted.
So I'm just dropping the intensity down
to a level two. Just going to elevate
the brow. So I need to place it in the
brow first. Turn the power on
and then backwards and forward.
Lights flash, groove tight. We're the
stars of this electricity.
[Music]
So, I'm literally over the bone here.
I'm not over the soft eyeball area or
anything. Angled up. So, the frequency
isn't entering the eye zone at all.
[Music]
I mean, seriously, look at that.
My eye is open. So, I guess I'm going to
fast forward through the other side now
and even things up.
So, now all that's left to do is just
focus on the outer part of the orbital
rim on the lower part and just onto the
upper cheek where you get the
development of the crows feet. I'm not
going to go on the soft tissue area
above the orbital rim. There's no need
for me to treat over there. And I do
have like a smaller device that I can
use for there for radio frequency and
EMS if I need to. Going to keep this on
at level two because again I'm just
looking for a mold stimulation in the
superficial layers.
So level two
and we're on. And this is really just
going to help to stimulate that collager
within the crow's feet. The lines and
the wrinkles that develop at the corner
of the eyes. Just kind of help really
plump them and lift them out.
And then before I forget, the piece deal
resistance is just above the brow.
So I'm just going to remove the excess
gel from my face and then we can do a
little bit of a sidebyside which is
going to show you immediately before I
started the treatment and immediately
after which is now.
I don't care that it's unbranded and
generic. I don't care that it's not the
most modern design. What I care about is
the results that it delivers. And for
me, this has never let me down. Sure,
you'll see reviews online of people
saying that it's not worked for them. A
lot of the time, that's because they're
not sure how to use the device. And I've
seen a lot of people saying afterwards
that they were using it thinking it was
active and it wasn't. I'm not
disregarding other people's experiences
and opinions on it, but when it comes to
seeing the reviews that some people
leave for this, I'm kind of led to
believe that it's coming from competitor
sellers that don't want this out selling
them or outperforming the tools and
devices that they currently have. So,
when you see a negative review with this
one, take it with a pinch of salt and
come back and have a look at my video
here or any of the other videos that
I've created in the past using this
device because you'll see that
consistently it performs and it
delivers. I mean, I just love it and you
can't go wrong. This is literally less
than like $100.
But yeah, I guess the main things to
remember with this is that when you're
first starting out with radio frequency,
start low and slow and take your time to
build up those collagen levels and
really understand how your skin is
responding to each treatment. That way,
you're not going to overtreat yourself.
You're not going to run the risk of
experiencing any kind of thermal burns
that are going to be really
uncomfortable and you just kind of have
a better control over the final outcome.
It's also really important to remember
that your skin needs time to rebuild
collagen. It doesn't just happen like
that. When you're using the higher
temperature devices like this one here,
you really don't want to overdo things
because really there's no point in
absolutely obliterating that collagen
before it's had a chance to kind of
become established. What you want to do
is you want to use the frequency to
target the weaker strands of collagen
that are in the skin and have those be
the ones that denature and then are
replaced with fresh collagen. So
basically, if you're constantly
depleting and destroying your collagen
before it has a chance to regenerate,
you're never really going to see the
kind of amazing results that radio
frequency can deliver.
So, is radio frequency a magic bullet
when it comes to anti-aging? Well, yes
and no. See, when it comes to anti-aging
skincare, you've got to tackle things on
multiple different levels. If you're
only focusing on the epidermis with
skincare topicals and activives, all
you're really going to do is kind of
resurface your skin slightly, help to
minimize the appearance of pores, of
hyperpigmentation. You're going to add a
little bit of hydration and kind of just
make your skin look really glowy and
dewy and plump. I don't know why I said
plump like that, but it's not going to
address the underlying issue of collagen
depletion. Now, youthful skin is loaded
with collagen and elastin. This is where
radio frequency really does become a bit
of a magic bullet and is by far one of
the best skin tightening treatments and
collagen boosting treatments out there.
When it comes to tackling the even
deeper layers like the smash layer,
which is basically the support for all
of the overlying tissues and muscles and
skin, for that I'm using Hiu. When it
comes to adding volume and strength and
support to my muscles, I'm using EMS.
So, as you can kind of see and gather
from this, the best results are always
going to come from a combination of
different devices, of different
modalities, and targeting the different
layers within the skin. But from my own
personal experience and also from my
training, radio frequency is definitely
something that shouldn't be overlooked
when it comes to trying to boost those
collagen levels in the skin to boost
that elastin to help tighten up the
visible appearance of the epidermis and
just kind of wind back time a little bit
on the appearance of your skin which is
going to leave you looking and feeling
visibly refreshed and rejuvenated. Now,
obviously, when it comes to getting the
most out of your radio frequency skin
treatments, especially if you're looking
at going down the professional incl
clinic route, then you'll definitely
want to have some discussions with your
dermatologist or aesthetician who are
going to be able to work with you and
develop a plan of action that's really
going to target and tackle all of those
little concerns that kind of bother you
and help restore that kind of youthful
volume and bounce back to your skin with
really tailored treatments that are
going to work best for you.
But yeah, if you've been wondering where
this has been hiding, it's not been
hiding. It's actually been in my studio
room. I do still use this. Now, I don't
use it as often as I used to because my
skin is actually a a place where I'm
really happy with it now. This was a
huge player in that and it's still
definitely going to serve me a purpose
way into the future. But yeah, it's been
really fun actually just doing a video
with this again and kind of bringing
this back to you guys. And I'm going to
be forever grateful to this one because
without this, my YouTube channel would
never have been created and I probably
never have got into skincare and the
industry like I have and I'd likely be
looking like Gollum right now. So, this
is going to forever be close to my
heart. So, thanks little guy. But, I'm
really interested to know if any of you
guys own this device or have used this
device in the past. Like, what are your
thoughts on it? or if you've got any
questions about this machine or about
radio frequency as a treatment or how
it's personally helped me elevate my
skincare game. The comments are now
open, so feel free to ask away. And
before you leave me, be sure to click on
like and subscribe for more skincare
science breakdowns and device
demonstrations. Thank you for joining me
for this video today. I hope that you
have a day that is as equally as
beautiful as you are and that you have
the best week ever. And I really look
forward to seeing you in my next video.
So till then, TJ over and out.
[Music]